Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
- Series XX: Objects
  - Decorated Bracelet Token ("Manila") Used as Slave Barter with African Chieftains, ca. 1750-1850; Location: Nigeria, West Africa (Box 33)
    Rudin # S - 579
  - Carved Carnelian Wax Seal Stamp for Letters - "Am I Not a Man and a Brother", ca. 1800; Format: Seal (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 225
  - Nine Three-Quarter Inch Buttons worn on Thomas H. Porter Slave Uniforms, ca. 1820s; Format: Buttons (Box 29)
    Rudin # S - 309
  - Bracelet Token ("Manila") Used as Slave Barter with African Chieftains, 1840s; Location: Recovered from wreck of British Scooner Duoro (Box 33)
    Rudin # S - 222
  - Lincoln Token - "Not One Cent For Slavery", 1860; Format: Coin (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 202
  - Anti-Slavery Token "Liberty and No Slavery", 1863; Format: COIN (Box 15, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 475
  - US Colored infantry Sutler token, 1864; Format: Token (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 1022
  - Lincoln medal commemorating the Emancipation Proclamation. Copper., 1871; Format: Medal (Box 15, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 855
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin Parian Pitcher displaying scenes based on the story, ca. 1873; Format: Pitcher (Box 31)
    Rudin # S - 800
  - Antique folding stereoscope and magnifier. Includes stereoview of landscape., ca. 1880; Format: Stereoscope (Box 37)
    Rudin # S - 857
  - Pair of Black Faced Meerschaum Smoking Pipes; One of Man with Slouch Hat; One of Man with Large Earrings, ca. 1880; Format: Pipes (Box 30)
    Rudin # S - 374
  - Cast Iron "Uncle Tom" mechanical bank, original paint, ca. 1885; Location: Philadelphia Format: Bank (Box 33)
    Rudin # S - 766
  - Frederick Douglass Memorial Spoon, 1895; Format: SPOON (Box 29)
    Rudin # S - 524
  - Sterling silver spoon with Confederate theme., ca. 1900; Location: Montgomery, Alabama Format: Spoon (Box 30)
    Rudin # S - 966
  - Bobbing Head Slave Child Bank, 19th c. (Box 39)
    Rudin # S - 699
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Bound Items
A Collection of All Such Acts of the General Assembly of Virginia, slave codes, 1803. Rudin # S - 464
Slave Broker James Eppinger's Letterbook. 1818-1830. Rudin # S - 427 (now 4681 Bd. Ms. 2++)
Slave Ledger Owned by Major John H. Drake. 1830-1850's. Rudin # S - 244 (now 4681 Bd. Ms. 1++)
Acts of a General Nature, Enacted, Revised and Ordered to be Reprinted, at the First Session of the Twenty-Ninth General Assembly of the State of Ohio, 1831. Rudin # S - 467
The Code of Virginia,1849. Slave laws. Rudin # S -528
Report of Naval Committee to the House of Representatives on Mail Steamships to Africa to Promote the Emigration of Free People of Color From the US to Liberia, 1850. Copy presented to William Seward and signed. Rudin # S - 396
The John Brown Raid - Robert E. Lee's Report Book, 1860. Rudin # S - 268
School History of the Negro Race in America from 1619 to 1890, Edward A. Johnson, 1894. Rudin # S - 333
New York at the Cotton States and International Exposition,1895. Rudin # S - 529
Monarchs of Minstrelsy: From 'Daddy' Rice to Date, Edw. Le Roy Rice, 1911. Signed by Larry McMurtry. Rudin # S - 516
From Slavery to Wealth, The Life of Scott Bond, signed by Scott Bond and Dan Rudd, 1917. Rudin # S - 543
Hampton and Its Students, MF Armstrong and Helen Ludlow. Containing one of the earliest compilations of slave songs. 1875. Rudin # S - 748
First Report to the Cotton Planters' Convention of Georgia, on the Agricultural Resources of Georgia, Joseph Jones, MD. 1860. Rudin # S - 852
The New Book of Nonsense. In Aid of the Sanitary Commission. 1864. Rudin # S - 672
Book of Bubbles. In Aid of the Sanitary Commission. 1864. Rudin # S - 672
The Eighth Census, Preliminary Report, 37th Congress, 1860. Rudin # S - 874
A Collection of All Such Acts of the General Assembly of Virginia, of a Public and Permanent Nature, as are Now in Force, with a New and Complete Index, 1803. Rudin # S - 870
Life and Times of Frederick Douglass, Frederick Douglass. His fourth autobiography. 1893. Rudin # S - 982
Ledger belonging to George Chapman, containing copies of wills, deeds and transactions, including slaves. Late 1600s-early 1800s. Rudin # S - 619
The Normal Song Book or Music Reader for Grammar and District Schools, Johnson and Osgood. 1851. Rudin # S - 1009
A Collection of Revival Hymns and Plantation Melodies, Marshal W. Taylor. Rudin # S - 1010
Beadle's Dime Song Book. Numbers 1-6 bound together. 1860. Rudin # S - 1013
The Singer's Own Book. 1841. Rudin # S - 1014
The New Man, Henry Clay Bruce, 1895. Rudin # S - 1032
Folk Song of the American Negro, John Wesley Work, 1915. Rudin # S - 1034
Plantation Sermons, or Plain and Familiar Discourses for the Instruction of the Unlearned, Rev. AF Dickson. Religious instruction intended for slaves. 1856. Rudin # S - 1036
The Draft Riots in New York, July 1863. The Metropolitan Police: Their Services During Riot Week. Their Honorable Record, David M. Barnes, 1863. Rudin # S - 1038